Iran is one of the most closed off countries in the world.
But for the past year,
something seems to have been changing.
In this Islamic regime,
ruled with an iron fist by the mullahs,
some women are daring to defy the rules and risking their lives in the process.
Across the big cities,
amid hijabs and chadors,
some women are shedding their headscarves.
This is the case for Gina.
Hello!
A young
32-year-old Iranian woman,
who has given up on more traditional clothing.
A move that's considered provocative by religious leaders.
I used to wear something around my neck
to go out in public or somewhere official
and I would cover my head.
But now I don't even wear a scarf around my neck.
I won't wear a hijab anymore.
It's a way to show that I am resisting.
Aren't you ashamed of doing that?
You don't have to do this.
I'm begging you!
Leave her alone!
Let go of me!
Some women are beaten and taken away by force.
Grab her!
According to Islamic law,
Gina could receive up to 72 lashes for not wearing the hijab.
We're not afraid anymore and we have to show
that we're protesting one way or another.
The young generation don't want to wear the hijab
anymore, unlike the previous generation.
To be able to dance freely.
Kiss freely,
For our brothers and sisters,
To change this backward way of seeing things.
For freedom!
In Iran there is a long list of things that are prohibited and women are on the front lines trying to reclaim more of their rights and freedoms.
Iran is a huge country of 90 million inhabitants neighboring Iraq and Afghanistan.
Since September 2022,
an unprecedented rebel movement started by women has been shaking the Islamic Republic.
Freedom, freedom, freedom.
It all started with the murder of Masha Jina Amini,
a young
22-year-old woman who was beaten to death by the authorities because she wasn't wearing her hijab correctly.
A photo taken at the hospital a few hours before her death did the rounds on social media.
Mashahjina Amini was a model student.
She was innocence personified.
This was a young, beautiful, provincial woman,
who came to Tehran just to visit the capital.
Many Iranian women saw themselves
in her tragic story
and this crystallised the already-huge anger
that Iranians were feeling.
Some women removed their hijabs as a form of protest.
And some even went as far as burning them with the support of some men.
A profound fury took hold of the country,
including in universities.
Amidst the chaos,
a slogan emerged.
Woman.
Life.
Freedom.
In response to their protests,
the authorities fired live bullets.
Allahu Akbar!
The violence was documented on social media.
It was impossible for a Western journalist to freely investigate in Iran.
So,
to tell this story of a country fighting for its rights,
we got in touch with Iranians via encrypted messaging.
They're going to share their experience.
Here, women wear the hijab in a really free and
relaxed way compared to other places in Tehran.
Are you here for me?
Get out!
Go.
Yes, put your clothes back on properly
and then come back.
They're all risking their lives by denouncing the Mullah dictatorship,
a regime that uses extensive censorship.
We must delete this part.
Corrupt dignitaries who hoard the country's wealth.
They keep it all for themselves.
They've created a group
and share everything out between them.
Determined authorities who terrorize their opponents beyond their borders.
I see my dad, he's been arrested,
he's in a car, blindfolded.
I'm heartbroken for him.
An investigation into this off-limits Iran,
where young people dream of freedom within a regime that continues to suppress it.
In Iran,
women can't openly talk about the oppression they suffer.
But behind closed doors,
we meet Gina,
the young woman who refuses to wear a hijab.
Hi girls, may God bless you.
This afternoon,
she has gone to the beauty salon.
Have you been there a long time?
Sit down, please.
A small slice of freedom far from the conservative and repressive Iran that lies outside.
How are you girls?
- Yeah, great!
See this colour? I love it.
- Yeah, you're right, it's great!
Within these walls,
women can discuss and laugh about anything at all.
When you go out without the hijab,
you have to do your hair, put some oil in it.
But you do it for yourself!
You're not doing if for men to look at.
They're going to fall out!
When I have a headscarf on my head
and I have to wear a long tunic,
I put lipstick on to feel seen, it makes me feel alive.
When you're in black all the time,
with gloomy clothing on, you look lifeless.
Exactly!
We dress how we want to
and say what we want to here.
Not like outside.
Being a woman is really hard!
They constantly belittle us.
Lots of women would prefer to not be a woman
and to live in a man's body.
The courage of Gina's generation amazes Mahjan,
who owns the salon.
At 40 years old,
she always wears the hijab outside.
My generation were also against it,
but we had no choice
because our parents forced us.
This generation is supported by my own.
So, it's easier for them to protest.
Gina's day-to-day life is similar to millions of Iranian women.
She's married and mothered to a little three-year-old boy,
Sorosh.
It's Poo, the bee.
Over time the young woman has learned to play by the Islamic rules.
For her clothes,
her wardrobe is divided into two.
Sadly, I've got two types of clothes.
Religious outfits like this one.
And in another wardrobe...
These are the outfits I wear around the house
or when I'm invited to a party.
I would like to only wear dresses like this one.
Like all women and girls around the world
Iwould like to dress like that to go out.
Not in the clothes they make me wear.
It's a horrible feeling.
Her husband condemns a regime that wants to control everything,
even when it means hiding the reality of the country.
The news channels aren't credible.
You can't believe what they say.
You can't trust them.
Nothing is reliable with this government.
It's impossible for young people to speak about their wish for freedom in the media.
So in recent months...
Once night falls,
Iranians like Gina have taken to shouting their anger from their windows.
Death to the government
that's killing our children!
Down with the dictatorship!
It's an easy form of resistance,
like taking off the hijab.
And
these Iranians don't hesitate to lash out directly at the head of the regime.
Like many Iranians,
Jina condemns a theocratic regime that is capable of murder if it means staying in power.
The faces of religious leaders are everywhere on the streets of the capital city Tehran.
Huge posters remind people of passages from the Quran.
The mullahs have been imposing Islamic law,
or Sharia law,
on the whole society for the past 44 years.
But many Iranians are doing everything they can to escape it.
Maryam,
who also refuses to wear the hijab,
wants to show us this new rebellious Tehran that infuriates the mullahs.
Hello! How much is this?
480,000 tomans
On a city centre street,
lingerie shops,
which were once hidden from public view,
now have shop displays that are considered risky.
Before, they hid the display behind fabric, but
they've taken it away, which I find interesting.
The conservative authorities even seem to have lost ground in the rich neighborhoods of northern Tehran.
In this ultra-modern shopping centre,
it almost seems like you're in Paris or New York.
Mariam can buy all Western fashion has to offer.
Jewellery,
luxury watches and even dresses by leading brands.
I'm in the Palladium shopping centre.
You can find products here
that don't exist anywhere else in Tehran.
To the great despair of religious leaders,
couples even walk hand in hand here,
and it's rare to see a girl in a hijab.
Most women wear the hijab
in a really free and relaxed way
compared to other places in Tehran.
Clothing fashion has changed.
It's not that the regime has accepted it.
It's not that the regime made this change.
It's women who have pulled back their rights
a tiny bit at a time.
In Islamic republic propaganda,
their idol is having women at home.
Women can't work without the agreement
of their husband
Women can't leave their house
if their husband doesn't agree.
A woman's life is worth half the life of a man.
That's in-the penal code.
This archaic vision of women's place in society is highlighted in the Mullahs'
propaganda on state television channels.
In this footage from February 2023,
Ali Khamenei,
who is the highest religious authority in Iran and aged 84,
takes center stage surrounded by hundreds of little girls who are covered from head to toe.
Mothers and daughters are all soldiers.
This is Iran.
Look at my country!
According to the supreme leader,
those who don't want to conform to Islamic law are enemies.
We will not allow this,
the government of the Islamic Republic
will settle the score with these criminals.
God is great!
Khamenei is our guide!
Long live the Islamic revolution.
clip produced by the authorities,
Madam, one moment!
Do not enter.
Put your hijab on.
A security officer asks women to cover themselves before being able to enter the underground.
Do it and then you'll be able to go in.
Thank you.
There's a deep dichotomy between Iranian society.
which is one of the most liberal in the world,
and the regime,
which is one of the most backwards.
As well as oppressing women,
the regime enforces mass censorship.
But this is another area in which Iranians are resisting.
Mariam,
our guide to rebel Tehran,
has led us to a little shop or a bookstore that is disobeying the Muller's orders.
In theory,
Western music is prohibited,
but here you can get your hands on records by the biggest international stars,
like the Village People and the Beatles.
And under a pile of books,
amazing souvenirs from an era when religious leaders weren't in power.
At that time, big musicians gave concerts in Iran.
Like Frank Sinatra.
Or Enrico Macias.
That was from a charity concert.
The music of Iran is the result
of the
We can't release anything
that's considered anti-religious.
So, books that mention sex, drugs or alcohol.
They have a problem with that.
Rules that infuriate Maryam.
We live in the same country but there's a really
big disconnect between the people on one side
and the leaders of the regime on the other.
The gap is huge.
It seems like we live in a parallel universe.
This young woman,
who works somewhere in Tehran as part of the regime censorship process,
has agreed to show us their radical methods.
The risk is exceptional.
Lots of Hollywood blockbusters have passed through her hands,
including one of the biggest successes in the history of cinema,
Titanic.
For a censor Titanio is a relatively easy film.
Their clothes are quite appropriate,
apart from in a few scenes.
It's a really important scene, the drawing scene.
You mustn't be able to see the folds of the breasts
and, even if it's not visible
the women's neckline must not be too low-cut.
I'm going to try and zoom in.
All the shots of the heroine undergo the same treatment.
They're re-framed to make her chest disappear.
The shoulders can be visible.
as long as we can't see the fold of the underarms.
But sometimes a scene is too revealing and zooming in won't suffice.
We must delete this part.
It's cut the scene down a lot but that's the way it is.
You know, in Iran, there are no uncensored films.
I'm sacrificing myself
by watching them before release.
I'm going to hell so that others can go to paradise.
That's just the way it is.
These ultra-purist rules infiltrating the everyday life of Iranians have not always existed.
At the start of the
1970s, the streets of Tehran looked like this.
Women wore skirts and the hijab was a rare sight.
At that time,
Iran was a monarchy.
Their king,
the Shah,
Mohammed Reza Pahlavi,
wanted to westernize his country.
Azadeh Kian is Iranian.
No one came up to you on the street
to ask you what you were wearing,
who you were going out with or walking with, etc.
When I tell my son now that when I was 15
we went dancing in discos that were reserved
for young people my age to go after school,
he doesn't believe me.
He suppressed any opposition and monopolized all wealth,
while most of the Iranian people lived in great poverty.
In 1978,
at the end of their tether,
the people rose up and demanded an end to the Shah's dictatorship.
Death to the Shah!
In the aftermath,
one face kept appearing,
that of a Shiite religious leader,
the Ayatollah Khomeini.
At that time,
he was a refugee in France,
in the small village of
Yvelins, Neuf.
Fleur Le Chateau.
By his side was Mohsen Sassegare,
a young militant Islamist.
I was only
22 years old and very impressive for me that a
78-year-old clergy who was at the focal point of most of the news of the world.
and the leadership of a revolution.
Journalists from around the world rushed to film this man as he prepared to overthrow the Shah.
The press even described him as a freedom fighter.
Ayatollah Khomeini could subject the creation
of the Islamic Republic to a popular vote.
A Republic that will guarantee
all freedoms of expression,
thought, worship or ideology, even Marxist.
These promises were never kept.
At the start of 1979,
under popular pressure,
the Shah relinquished power and the Ayatollah returned to Tehran as a hero.
Then he founded the first Islamic Republic in the world,
with a parliament and a president,
just like any democracy.
But in reality,
Ayatollah Khomeini seized all power and established a religious dictatorship.
He became the Supreme Leader, that is to say
he was absolute power personified.
The Supreme Leader is the real president.
The Supreme Leader is the commander-in-chief
of the armed forces.
The Supreme Leader is the person
who is named for life.
His first followers,
including Mohsen Sassegara,
felt betrayed.
Make heaven and the earth,
a spiritual regime,
a new way in politics.
We didn't know that such a way would take the way.
We realised he'd lied to us.
We realised there would be a regression
in terms of women's rights.
For example, the legal age of marriage for girls
was 18 years old under the Shah
but it was brought back to 9 years old
under the Islamic regime.
The world was outraged and Iran withdrew from the international stage.
Today,
more than three out of four Iranians would like the Mullahs'
dictatorship to end.
Since September 2022 and the murder of Masha Amini,
who was beaten to death by the Morality Police,
people have been attacking all symbols of the regime.
Molotov cocktails thrown at mosques,
portraits of religious leaders burned in public,
propaganda posters destroyed and anti-regime tags graffitied.
Across the country,
thousands of Iranians are unwavering.
in their defiance of the authorities.
In autumn 2022,
high schools and universities became impassioned about the issue and took to the streets.
The authorities feared a youth rebellion more than anything.
So they ordered students to be arrested,
as this confidential internal memo that we have managed to obtain shows.
It came from the Supreme National Security Council and is addressed to the Minister of Education.
The disruptive constituents must be arrested outside of their educational establishments and handed over to the judicial authorities.
Hundreds of arrests followed.
What was more surprising was that thousands of schoolgirls were also victims of mysterious gas attacks.
The gas used caused nausea,
vomiting and breathing problems.
Despite strong suspicions against them,
the authorities denied all involvement.
Very soon after,
to quieten the widespread uprising,
the regime decided to employ even more barbaric methods.
It gave the order to open fire on protesters.
Those in power used weapons of war against its own people.
Lift him up!
Thousands of people were wounded.
How did he save them?
As soon as you step foot in the street in Iran
to protest,
to oppose the regime or even if you sing
the shortest slogan against the Supreme Leader,
you risk your life.
These scenes of extremely violent repression happen over and over again across the country,
and leave hundreds dead.
530 people dead, including around 60 children
and 38 women.
They're the sort of figures that make your head spin
and allow us in a way to measure
the breadth of the repression in Iran
and shows what the regime is capable of.
The regime defines itself
as the incarnation of Islam.
Therefore, if you act against the regime, to them
that's as if you're acting against the religion itself.
In only six months,
at least 20,000 people were arrested.
A woman who was victim to this repression after attending several protests
wanted to share her experience.
She dares to speak out because she has managed to flee Iran.
I've decided to speak out
because the world needs to understand
what's happening in the Islamic republic.
Elahi is a young human rights activist who has already been imprisoned several times,
notably in the dreaded Evin prison in Tehran.
on.
When you're imprisoned there, firstly they
interrogate you, then they put you in isolation.
They give you two ruined and dirty blankets,
so you put one over yourself
and use the other as a cushion.
Most of the country's political and intellectual prisoners are being held at Evin.
In this prison footage,
which was accessed by a group of hackers,
detainees can be seen being dragged across the floor,
hit and squeezed into cells.
It's a very bleak place.
There are no lights.
You don't know what time it is, if it's day or night.
You have no way to tell how much time has passed.
At the end of November 2022,
the young human rights activist was arrested at home,
and this time she was taken by force to a secret detention centre.
I was blindfolded the whole time.
I was harassed and tortured.
They made me take off my clothes,
in fact, they took them off by force.
They started to humiliate me by mocking my body.
They said my skin was ugly
and then they started to touch me...
Elaye was a victim of sexual assault.
I'm really sorry.
These pro-regime militia,
whatever they're fucking called,
what they want is to destroy the souls of women
and scare others.
The regime is only holding on through fear.
It's important to understand that this is
a psychological war led by the regime
against its own citizens
to eventually establish a regime of terror.
This sexual violence and mass imprisonment has one precise goal,
to terrorise the people of Iran.
And the regime has gone even further.
It makes heavy use of the death penalty.
It often takes place in public.
Many of the condemned are hanged using a crane.
In 2022 alone,
at least 582 people were executed.
Among them were some very young protesters.
22-year-old
Mohamed Mahdi Karami was a karateka.
23-year-old Mohsen Sheikha was a waiter in a cafe.
And
23-year-old...
Majee Reza Ranavad was a fruit and vegetable seller.
He was executed on the 12th of December 2022.
None of the people who were publicly hanged had the right to a fair trial.
And because of this,
Iranian lawyers are also targeted.
There's your photo.
With the hijab.
Ah yes, the hijab.
He is wearing a hijab.
Ehsan Hosseinzadeh and his wife Soheila are both refugees and have been living in France since 2019.
They had to leave their country with their little boy after receiving death threats for defending protesters.
Sit down here.
Seven-year-old Ayhan is in his first year of school and is learning to read.
Go on, read.
and went to the camp.
When?
When my grandpa arrived.
Do you remember Iran, Ayhan?
Yes.
What do you remember?
- The Azadi tower.
What does Azadi mean?
- Freedom.
Freedom.
The family had to leave in a hurry,
so they could only bring a few keepsakes with them.
That's our law office in Tehran.
I saw two people and they started to interrogate me.
'Why are you carrying out activities
against the regime?
I was in shock.
Every moment we waited, we felt that at
any moment they will come looking for us.
We were ready to go to prison.
The threats were serious.
Ehsan regularly receives calls for help from his colleagues who are still in Iran.
The president of the Bar has sent us a message.
Apparently, they're checking all our facts
and our gestures.
Over the course of these past few months, you know,
more than 50 lawyers have been arrested in Iran
and tortured just for defending
political prisoners in Iran:
According to Ehsan Hosseinzadeh,
most of the condemned people hadn't done anything wrong.
These people aren't criminals.
They're citizens who wanted to protest
against the regime,
but the regime can't accept
that 80% of its society are against them.
And to judge the protesters,
the regime uses special jurisdictions,
revolutionary tribunals.
In these sham trials,
which are broadcast live on television,
the accused have just a few minutes to defend themselves,
and the magistrates enforce religious law.
We aspire to and try hard to administer justice
thanks to God and according to the will of God.
The main mission of these tribunals is
to protect the existence of the Islamic Republic.
The judges aren't independent.
The lawyers that attend the hearings are lawyers
who have been chosen by the judicial authorities.
In this footage,
Mohamed Mahdi Karami,
a young
22-year-old man who took part in protests at the start of November,
is accused of having killed a member of the religious police.
The martyr Seyed Rouhollah Ajamian
member of law enforcement,
was trying to regulate the crowd
and reestablish use of a bus lane.
He was attacked by one of the troublemakers,
in a terrible and dishonourable way,
and was a victim of several stab wounds.
The accused also chanted anti-government slogans,
in an attempt to create chaos.
He's been accused of "moharebeh"
war against God.
That means he'll be punished
in a very violent way, by execution.
On social media,
Mohamed Mahdi Karami's parents begged the authorities to spare their son.
He has several national titles.
I'm Mohammad Madhi Karami's father.
My son has been sentenced to death.
beg you to stop his execution.
I am his mother and I'm asking you
to please stop his execution.
Despite their calls for clemency,
their son would be hanged just two months after his arrest.
Since the protests have started,
the number of hangings has practically doubled.
This ultra-violent Iranian regime doesn't only terrorize people in its own country.
It hunts down its opponents well beyond its borders.
In November 2022,
the British secret services warned the whole world during this press conference.
Iran projects threat to the UK directly through its aggressive intelligence services.
At its sharpest,
this includes ambitions to kidnap or even kill
British or UK-based individuals perceived as enemies of the regime.
We've seen at least 10 such potential threats since January alone.
No Iranian opponent can feel 100% at ease and safe
whether they're in New York, Paris or London.
Unbelievably,
a
19-year-old girl agreed to tell us about the awful kidnapping of her father by the Iranian secret services.
He was a famous political objector to the Mullahs'
regime.
I miss him.
I always think I'd love him to come back
just for one moment.
A refugee in France since 2012,
Nia's father,
Rouhullah,
presented a news channel followed by more than one million people on the platform Telegram.
There,
he condemned abusers of the Iranian regime.
He was the regime's number one enemy.
He was threatened several times:
"We're going to kill you on the streets.
On the Saturday night, he called and told us,
"I've arrived in Irag, I'm at the hotel,
everything's fine.
And on Monday,
I was at school, and I got a message
from one of my Iranian friends that said
"Niaz, is your dad at home with you right now?"
I said, "No" and she sent me a link.
I clicked on it...
I see my dad, he's been arrested,
he's in a car, blindfolded.
In this foutage broatcast by an Iranian television channel
Nia find out that her father had been arrested by an iranian commando
Mullah’ is filmed in a car
witch would take him from Irak to Iran by force
And that same evening, he confessed on TV.
I watched it on TV.
I am Rouhollah Zam, founder of the site Amad News.
I regret what has happened these past three or four
years, the interviews I gave to the medias.
I also regret having trusted foreign States,
like the French State.
I'm heartbroken for him.
Naturally, given the events, I must apologise
to the whole of the regime.
It makes me so angry.
The
pro-regime press celebrated Rouala's capture.
A few weeks later,
he was found guilty of espionage and of insulting the sacred character of Islam.
spoke to him one last time on the phone.
He said "My darling, how are you?
Know that lots of things are going to happen
but whatever happens you keep studying
and don't give up anything.
I said to him, "What do you mean?
What's going to happen?
Why are you saying goodbye?"
I ask him, "When is prayer time?"
because in Iran they execute at prayer time,
so morning prayers at 4.30-5am.
5.00.
He said,
the prayer is in 30 minutes.
Okay...
Rojolla was executed 48 hours after his conviction.
Oh, it's really hard...
Every time there's an execution, I'm furious.
I'm filled with hatred.
The dramatic capture of Rojolla was incited by the armed branch of the religious authorities,
the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps.
This elite group,
made up of 125,000 men,
has land force and even its own marine.
In 2019,
the American government listed the paramilitary group as a terrorist organization.
Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps Land Forces
The Islamic Revolutionary Guards have no limit.
They have no problem directly threatening citizens of Western countries that dare to criticize the Islamic Republic.
In January 2023,
when Charlie Hebdo published caricatures of Iranian dignitaries entitled,
Mullahs,
Go Back Where You Came From,
The commander-in-chief of the guards,
General Salami,
named the journalists of the weekly publication as targets and called for them to be killed.
The objective of the Revolutionary Guard Corps
is to protect the regime.
In that way, it's an ideological army.
In any case, their name says it all:
they're the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps
not the Iranian Guard Corps.
The Revolutionary Guards were created
to protect the system.
As well as protecting the regime,
the Revolutionary Guards also defend the particular interests of Iranian leaders.
They have a stranglehold on all key sectors of the economy.
For this reason,
they've created several holding companies,
such as Khatam al-Anbija,
which is worth more than $10 billion.
Khatam al-Anbija Reconstruction Headquarters has moved towards super projects.
This company,
with its opaque finances,
manages oil and gas fields,
hydro dams and even public transport.
These days, we're talking about
60% of the Iranian economy
being in the hands of the Revolutionary Guards
via companies that are directly affiliated with them
or companies that are closely linked to them.
Clearly in Iran, it's very difficult to do business
without identifying yourself to the Revolutionary
Guards, and without them profiting.
In Iran, you can't really invest
you can't do anything if you're an entrepreneur
or a big businessman
without the regime allowing you.
This monopoly on wealth,
held by the dignitaries of the regime who were extremely corrupt,
is one of the causes of the extreme poverty that affects almost one in two Iranians today.
Kitchen knife, vegetable knife.
Peeler! Ladies, gentlemen...
Since the intensification of international economic sanctions imposed on Iran,
In 2018,
for not respecting the nuclear agreement,
the situation has worsened to a dangerous extent.
Prices jump up by 40%
every year.
In Karaj,
a city of 1.5 million inhabitants to the west of Tehran,
communities have been hit hard.
Hello! Excuse me...
The eggs are 400,000 rials.
Do you remember how much they were before?
Yeah.
How much was it?
Ithink it was 320,000 rials, was it?
That wasn't long ago.
Yeah, I think so.
- In two days, it's already gone up.
Well, wait and see what it is in a few more days.
My God...
For example, fish.
don't eat fish anymore.
And even basic dishes, like a bolognaise
now I make that with soya.
I don't eat much pasta with meat.
Maybe one a month.
The value of Iranian currency,
the rial,
is constantly falling.
It's worth ten times less than it was in
It falls every month, every week, every day...
When you're part of the middle class,
you're getting poorer day by day.
Ali can only take out two million rials.
That's the maximum I can withdraw.
This is the
I'm really worried.
As a young man of 29, I don't have a future.
Ali is a craftsman.
He makes fabric dolls.
Once a week he sells them on a stall set up at the side of the road.
Please take a look.
Those in that box are 450,000
but I can do you a deal.
And that one?
- With the jumper around the vase, that's 100,000.
But at the moment business isn't good.
No one can afford to buy anything.
The situation is getting worse.
It's not a crisis, it's a catastrophe!
I've been doing this for 7 or 8 months now.
It seems like the government is doing all they can
to ensure we can't live comfortably.
They want our daily lives to be unbearable
so that we don't have any strength to protest.
Ali may well hate the Islamic Republic,
but he makes them richer every time he has to fill his tanker.
All the petrol stations in the country link back to the regime.
This will belong to either a member of
the government or a member of the Guards.
They're involved in everything:
They keep it all for themselves.
They've created a group
and share everything out between them.
Every day,
Ali spends more than ten hours in his car,
only to make the equivalent of ten to fifteen euros a day.
I want to leave the country.
Today, you can ask anyone, and they'd
tell you they'd like to leave the country.
Why doesn't he want to?
Who doesn't want to?
If you ask three people,
three people want to leave.
We're headed to Guyane,
in the north of Iran.
In this more traditional agricultural inland area,
people are starting to also have doubts.
Yet,
they still attend the mosque every Friday.
Reza is 72.
He has always lived in this small town of 5,000 inhabitants.
Hello.
How are you?
I know everyone here.
These are devout people, they work hard.
Father to five children,
Reza mainly makes a living from his garden.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
I've got garlic,
I've got broad beans, most of the things
that people eat, I produce them myself.
And that's enough for my family's needs.
Hello. May God keep you.
- Hello, how are you?
Good, thanks.
As it's nearing the end of May,
his employees have started to sow the seeds.
That's the shell of the grains of rice.
We put them on top of the seedlings,
which protects them from the frost and the heat.
Reza drops his harvest off at a trader's near the market.
You can find all the typical products of Guyane along these market stalls.
But Reza is worried,
since the price of rice keeps going up.
His wholesaler has noticed a fall in demand.
Hello.
For the rice, it's been 7 months
since we've had a buyer.
There's very little activity right now.
People aren't coming to the market as much.
No one has any money to come
and buy anything here.
How much is that today?
That's 800,000 rials.
OK.
And here's the smoked rice.
-Ah, that's smoked. And how much is it?
That's 1,000.000 rials but we've no buyers.
We've been living on our savings
for nine months now.
90% of people don't eat anything
other than bread now.
This anger is spreading all over the country.
According to an independent study by Gaman,
a specialist polling institute,
in Iran,
fewer than two out of every ten Iranians today support the religious authorities.
But a year since the death of Masha Amini,
there is no let-up in their repression.
According to the NGO
Iran Human Rights,
almost 500 people have already been executed since January 2023.